

Dexter Crago

Full Stack Software Engineer

My Personal Website

in LinkedIn 🔘 GitHub

dexter18crago@gmail.com

Hello! I'm Dexter, a full stack software engineer with a strong grasp of programming and code design fundamentals, experience building 30+ projects from scratch, and a strong drive to continue learning and improving my skills. Please feel free to check out my personal website of to see some of my work and learn more about me and how I can start adding value to your team right away. I look forward to hearing from you soon!

Professional Experience

Outlier, Software Engineer - Contract

Jun 2024 – present

- Evaluating the quality of Al-generated code
- Engaging in a cycle of feedback and improvement
- Solving coding problems
- Writing functional and efficient code
- Writing test cases to confirm code works efficiently
- Creating instructions to help others

Stevensville High School, *Science Teacher*

Jan 2023 – Apr 2023

- Managed 100+ students across a variety of subjects
- Time management, organization, self-discipline
- Critical and creative thinking skills
- · Conflict resolution skills
- Conducted, analyzed, and presented research

Montana Club, Server

Jun 2015 – Mar 2021

- Increased sales from \$500 to \$1000/day in one year
- Worked both in the front and in the back to better understand the whole operation
- Trusted with closing out registers containing \$1000+
- Trained junior co-workers

City Life Community Center, *Youth Worker*

Jun 2018 – Jun 2020

- Working closely with a team to coordinate trips and events for 20+ students
- Fully engaged in professional development
- Constantly considering how to better serve students
- · Adaptable, teachable, and self-directed

Education

Full Stack Software Engineering, The Odin Project

Aug 2023 - May 2024

- Created 30+ projects from scratch
- Creating frontends with HTML, CSS, JS, and React
- Creating backends with NodeJS and ExpressJS
- Managing MongoDB databases with Mongoose ODM
- Tests with Jest and authentication with PassportJS
- Version control with Git and sending data with JSON
- Creating and consuming REST APIs
- Fundamental data structures and algorithms
- Agile software development workflow
- Writing clean, efficient, and maintainable code that follows industry best practices and coding standards

Bachelor of Science, Montana State University

Aug 2018 – May 2023

- Secondary Education Broadfield Science
- Strong logical reasoning and analysis skills
- Able to easily break down large problems
- Great at communicating complex technical concepts to both technical and non-technical audiences
- · Using a testing mindset to pinpoint issues
- Brainstorming creative solutions to a problem

</> Skills

HTML • CSS • JavaScript • Git VCS •

React.js • Jest • JSON • RESTAPIs •

Node.js • Express.js • NoSQL • JWT •

MongoDB • Mongoose ODM • Passport.js